<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Bridge on Tilly Net</title>
    <link>https://blog.tillynet.com/tags/linux-bridge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux Bridge on Tilly Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tillynet.com/tags/linux-bridge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Internet Connectivity Issues for Proxmox VMs on a Routed Subnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.tillynet.com/my-home-lab-journey/resolving-internet-connectivity-issues-for-proxmox-vms-on-a-routed-subnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tillynet.com/my-home-lab-journey/resolving-internet-connectivity-issues-for-proxmox-vms-on-a-routed-subnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post documents the troubleshooting process I followed to resolve an internet connectivity issue affecting virtual machines (VMs) hosted on a Proxmox VE node running on a Wi-Fi-only Dell XPS 15. The VMs were deployed on a routed internal subnet (&lt;code&gt;172.30.30.0/24&lt;/code&gt;) with static routes configured through a pfSense firewall. While the VMs could communicate with internal hosts—including DNS and gateway IPs—they were unable to reach external internet addresses such as &lt;code&gt;8.8.8.8&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Proxmox Node on a Wi-Fi-Only Dell XPS Laptop</title>
      <link>https://blog.tillynet.com/my-home-lab-journey/deploying-a-proxmox-node-on-a-wi-fi-only-dell-xps-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tillynet.com/my-home-lab-journey/deploying-a-proxmox-node-on-a-wi-fi-only-dell-xps-laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I document how I deployed Proxmox VE on a Dell XPS 15 laptop with no physical Ethernet interface. This machine was added to my home lab as a standalone hypervisor, running independently from my main Protectli-based Proxmox node.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because the XPS lacks wired connectivity, I had to work through some unique networking constraints, including bridging over Wi-Fi and enabling connectivity for guest virtual machines. This write-up covers the initial NAT-based setup and the transition to a cleaner routed network model with static routes via pfSense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
